<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>classification | Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tag/classification/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/classification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>classification</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>classification</title>
      <link>/tag/classification/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survey on mobility data. A supervised classification approach for area identification</title>
      <link>/publication/milan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/milan/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milan mobility project</title>
      <link>/project/milan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/milan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project we made a comparative study between clustering analysis,
which is typically used in mobility scenarios, and supervised classifica-
tion for the identification of home and work zones of an area. We will use
a mobility dataset from the city of Milan to achieve this. Using passive
mobile positioning data offers a powerful tool to study the geography
and the mobility of the population. With the available data, we will try to
identify workplaces and residential areas using both supervised classifica-
tion and clustering. In order to generate training data for the classification
model, we manually label several sub-regions of the available grid, one
with random cells and another with a 20-by-20 resolution. Experimental
results show that the kNN algorithm provides an acceptable accuracy
that could be able to predict if a cell represent a working or a residential
area for the full grid, thanks to the semi-supervised approach used in
learning from a manually-labeled region. However, the results provided
with k-means and k-medoids clustering show that it is not able to accom-
plish the former idea, instead it focuses on identifying the mobile traffic
distribution around the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experiment and its results are available in the Github repository linked.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
